<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snapcraft on </title>
    <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/snapcraft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snapcraft on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 14:48:31 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/snapcraft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft 3.1</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 14:48:31 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.1/</guid>
      <description>snapcraft 3.1 is now available on the stable channel of the Snap Store. This is a new minor release building on top of the foundations laid out from the snapcraft 3.0 release.
If you are already on the stable channel for snapcraft then all you need to do is wait for the snap to be refreshed.
The full release notes are replicated here below
Build Environments It is now possible, when using the base keyword, to once again clean parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft 3.0</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 16:47:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.0/</guid>
      <description>The release notes for snapcraft 3.0 have been long overdue. For convenience I will reproduce them here too.
Presenting snapcraft 3.0 The arrival of snapcraft 3.0 brings fresh air into how snap development takes place!
We took the learnings from the main pain points you had when creating snaps in the past several years, and we we introduced those lessons into a brand new release - snapcraft 3.0!
Build Environments As the cornerstone for behavioral change, we are introducing the concept of build environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft Build Environments</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-build-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 17:47:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-build-environments/</guid>
      <description>Prologue After a week away from my computer I want to organize my thoughts on the progress made towards build VMs by providing this write up since that forum post can be a bit overwhelming if you are casually wanting to keep up to date.
The reasons for this feature work to exist, for those not up to speed, is that we want to have a very consistent build environment for which anyone building a project can have an expectable outcome of a working snap (or non working one if it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbuConLA 2017 Summit Summary</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2017-summit-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 13:29:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2017-summit-summary/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes about UbuconLA, a bit of social activities and thoughts on the talks related to the snappy ecosystem.
Arriving I left late on thursday for a planned night arrival into Lima, Leo was going to be arriving around 2 hours earlier than me flying in from Costa Rica.
Once the plane I was on coming from Cordoba, Argentina landed into Lima I got onto an ad-hoc telegram group we had created and mentioned that I had landed and discovered Leo was still trying to Uber out of there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making your snaps available to the store using snapcraft</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/making-your-snaps-available-to-the-store-using-snapcraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 13:58:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/making-your-snaps-available-to-the-store-using-snapcraft/</guid>
      <description>Now that Ubuntu Core has been officially released, it might be a good time to get your snaps into the Store.
Delivery and Store Concepts So let&amp;rsquo;s start with a refresher on what we have available on the Store side to manage your snaps.
Every time you push a snap to the store, the store will assign it a revision, this revision is unique in the store for this particular snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Snapcraft Parts Ecosystem</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/the-snapcraft-parts-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 12:57:07 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/the-snapcraft-parts-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Today I am going to be discussing parts. This is one of the pillars of snapcraft (together with plugins and the lifecycle).
For those not familiar, this is snapcraft&amp;rsquo;s general purpose landing page, http://snapcraft.io/ but if you are a developer and have already been introduced to this new world of snaps, you probably want to just go and hop on to http://snapcraft.io/create/
If you go over this snapcraft tour you will notice the many uses of parts and start to wonder how to get started or think that maybe you are duplicating work done by others, or even better, maybe an upstream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcrafting a kernel</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcrafting-a-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 21:06:57 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcrafting-a-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With snapcraft 2.5 which can be installed on the upcoming 16.04 Xenial Xerus with apt or consumed from the 2.5 tag on github we have included two interesting plugins: kbuild and kernel.
The kbuild plugin is interesting in itself, but here we will be discussing the kernel plugin which is based out of the kbuild one.
A note of caution though, this kernel plugin is still not considered production ready.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>