<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on </title>
    <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 13:29:02 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UbuConLA 2017 Summit Summary</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2017-summit-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 13:29:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2017-summit-summary/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes about UbuconLA, a bit of social activities and thoughts on the talks related to the snappy ecosystem.
Arriving I left late on thursday for a planned night arrival into Lima, Leo was going to be arriving around 2 hours earlier than me flying in from Costa Rica.
Once the plane I was on coming from Cordoba, Argentina landed into Lima I got onto an ad-hoc telegram group we had created and mentioned that I had landed and discovered Leo was still trying to Uber out of there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linaro Connect BKK16</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/bkk16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 17:31:57 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/bkk16/</guid>
      <description>Just a week ago I made my way back from Linaro Connect. It is my first time at a Linaro Connect that was not jointly done with a UDS and even then I did not participate in the event. It was also my first time in Thailand and to a greater extent Asia so I was very interested in going.
The main purpose for attending was to show snappy and in particular, snapcraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbuCon and SCaLE 2016 trip report</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubucon-and-scale-2016-trip-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 16:31:57 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubucon-and-scale-2016-trip-report/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally taking some time to wite about things that happened during UbuCon and SCaLE. I am really grateful for Canonical as without the sponsorship I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been there at all.
UbuCon UbuCon is where was I was mostly involved, I had a scheduled lightning talk, a proper talk that I gave out with Manik and also actively involved in 3 unconference sessions.
Presenting Plenary talk The day started with some an intro to the UbuCon Summit and what it was all about followed by a keynote from Mark Shuttleworth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UbuConLA 2015 Summary</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2015-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 13:29:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/ubuconla-2015-summary/</guid>
      <description>This is a post I never got to publish from way back.
 About UbuConLA Last week I attended the 2015 edition of UbuConLA, a successor to what once was UDS, the Ubuntu Developer Summit which later transformed into vUDS, the v standing for virtual which eventually was renamed to Ubuntu Online Summit. UbuConLA, fully organized by the community, tries to relive the days of UDS for a chance to see face to face with fellow Ubuntu contributors or contributors to be or just people generally interested in Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>