<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on </title>
    <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 14:05:04 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.sergiusens.org/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft 3.3</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 14:05:04 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.3/</guid>
      <description>snapcraft 3.3 is now available on the stable channel of the Snap Store. This is a new minor release building on top of the foundations laid out from the snapcraft 3.0 release.
If you are already on the stable channel for snapcraft then all you need to do is wait for the snap to be refreshed.
The full release notes are replicated here below
Core base: core In order to use the new features of snapcraft, introduced with 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broader use of bases for snaps</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/broader-use-of-bases-for-snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 12:18:53 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/broader-use-of-bases-for-snaps/</guid>
      <description>We have regular Engineering Sprints at Canonical. These are a great opportunity for engineering teams to come together and discuss progress and roadmaps, as well as code and work together. Many of us have just returned from one such event in Malta, getting home just before the widely report storm hit the island (see Destruction across Malta as gale-force winds batter islands).
And one of the things we discussed over the course of that week was the implications of using bases when snaps use type other than app (a base is a special kind of snap that provides a minimal set of libraries common to most applications).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft 3.1</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 14:48:31 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.1/</guid>
      <description>snapcraft 3.1 is now available on the stable channel of the Snap Store. This is a new minor release building on top of the foundations laid out from the snapcraft 3.1 release.
If you are already on the stable channel for snapcraft then all you need to do is wait for the snap to be refreshed.
The full release notes are replicated here below
Build Environments It is now possible, when using the base keyword, to once again clean parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft 3.0</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 16:47:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-3.0/</guid>
      <description>The release notes for snapcraft 3.0 have been long overdue. For convenience I will reproduce them here too.
Presenting snapcraft 3.0 The arrival of snapcraft 3.0 brings fresh air into how snap development takes place!
We took the learnings from the main pain points you had when creating snaps in the past several years, and we we introduced those lessons into a brand new release - snapcraft 3.0!
Build Environments As the cornerstone for behavioral change, we are introducing the concept of build environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapcraft Build Environments</title>
      <link>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-build-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 17:47:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sergiusens.org/posts/snapcraft-build-environments/</guid>
      <description>Prologue After a week away from my computer I want to organize my thoughts on the progress made towards build VMs by providing this write up since that forum post can be a bit overwhelming if you are casually wanting to keep up to date.
The reasons for this feature work to exist, for those not up to speed, is that we want to have a very consistent build environment for which anyone building a project can have an expectable outcome of a working snap (or non working one if it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>